Guide to the Yale University Art, Architecture, and Art History Theses and Projects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Art, architecture, and art history theses and projects, Yale University
1915-2018
RU 259
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
74.29
9324068.81
The materials consist of research papers, theses, and projects by students in art, art history, and architecture programs at Yale.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Existence and Location of Copies
The illustrations for Helen M. Manner's thesis "Romanesque Architecture of Viterbo" are available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM206. The plates for Pamela Z. Blum's thesis on the Salisbury Cathedral Chapter House (1 reel, 35mm) are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM207.
Scope and Contents
Included are papers and projects on art and architecture prepared by students at Yale University. The bulk of the papers date from 1915 to 1977, a period when the various sponsoring schools and departments formed and reformed under various names. The School of Fine Arts was opened in 1866 and a full professional course in architecture, was added in 1913. In 1958 the name of the school was changed to the School of Art and Architecture. In 1972 it was divided in to two parts: the School of Art and the School of Architecture, granting degrees of Master of Fine Arts, Master of Architecture and Master of Environmental Design. The Department of the History of Art in the Graduate School offers a program of courses leading to a Doctor of Philosophy.
The papers in Part I are of two kinds: research papers and theses on art and papers or constructions on design problems for the years 1915 through 1970. The identifying information on the, manuscripts themselves manuscripts themselves author, title, degree, date has been supplemented from the Catalogue of Officers and Graduates of Yale University (1701-1924), the Catalogue of Yale University Alumni (1925-1954), and commencement programs (1955-1970). Additions from these sources are bracketed, and question marks have been inserted to call attention to inconsistencies and uncertainties with respect to date and degree. The entry in the "Year" column is the date of the thesis or research paper. When the degree was awarded in a later year, that date follows the designation of the degree in the "Title" column. Slides and photographs of the student's work are reported as "Slides" and "Portfolio," respectively, but other illustrations (diagrams, reproductions, etc.) are not mentioned in the folder listing. The count of pages is approximate.
Part II is divided in to two sections. Section I contains edited transcripts of the master class in the School of Art and Architecture from October 1966 to January 1967. Section II is made up of master class projects prepared by students in 1953 and between 1959 and 1966.
Part III contains master's theses and research papers written for the Department of the History of Art, the now superseded School of Fine Arts, the former programs in environmental design, leading to a Master of Environmental Design (M.E.D.) and the program in city planning which awarded a Master of City Planning (M.C.P.).
Part IV is made up of additional papers arranged numerically by accession.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged as follows: I. Theses and Research Papers, 1915-1970. II. Master's Class, 1959-1966. III. Theses and Research Papers, 1934-1977. IV. Numerical Series, 1915-1982; and subsequent accessions.
Architecture; Art students; Art -- History; Art; Born digital; Theses; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Architecture; Yale University. School of Art
- Art, architecture, and art history theses and projects, 1915-1996; Series I
  - Abeshouse, Jordan. Adolescent Art Education. M.F.A. 49 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ackerman, Harry G. The Shades Speak. B.F.A. 39 p., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agee, Philip Clay. Look at the Slides First. M.F.A. 14 p., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ake, Nancy [C.]. Painting in the United States during the Industrial Revolution B.F.A. 17 p., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Robert L. Arts and Crafts. B.F.A. 11 p., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alvord, Muriel. The Mural Paintings of Violet Oakley. B.F.A. 15 P, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Arthur J. The Development of Color. B.F.A. 42 p., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anderson, Arthur J. A Summation of the Development of Paul Klee's Drawings. M.F.A. 24 p, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anderson, M[alcolm] G. Government in Art. B.F.A. 25 p., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aument, Carroll M., Jr. Form Description in Drawing. B.F.A. 11 P., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Axton, John T. Contemporary Esthetics and the Esthetic Experience. M.F.A. 39 p, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Azerrad, Joel. On Photography. B.F.A. 20 p., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Aziz, Philip John. Post 7. B.F.A. 31 P., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aziz, Philip John. Art and the Ordained. M.F.A. 90 p., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bacon, Agnes W. Study of Professor Cizek's Teaching: His Methods, and their Practicality. 4 p., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bailey, William H. An Introductory Drawing Course (Secondary School Level). B.F.A. 33 p., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bailey, William H. Some Methods of Articulating Volume and Space in Drawing (See: box 11, folder 543)
  - Bain Herbert J. Greaves. An Investigation of Optical Mixtures and its Use by the Impressionist Painters and in Photographic Reproductions. B.F.A. 43 p., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baker, David. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 7p. Slides., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Baljian, Nvart Rose. Russian Icons. B.F.A. 27 p., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bardazzi Peter. Untitled Thesis. M.F.A. 27 p. Portfolio., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Barer Miriam Anne. Woodcut Illustration; with Emphasis on the Books of Fifteenth Century Germany. B.F.A. 14 p., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barger Raymond G. A Treatise for Young Sculptors on the Subject of Enlarging. B.F.A. 18 p., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Barnard Jere Norris. On My work-1965-1967. M.F.A. 10 p. Slides. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barress Philip B. Color: Its Concept and Relation to the Painter. B.F.A. 14 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Batty James A. Polychromy. B.F.A. 18 p., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bauer Sally [L.]. Piero Della Francesca: His Concepts of Color and Form. B.F.A. 29 p., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bayard Donald Duer. A General Chronology of American Furniture Styles with Accompanying European Influences. B.F.A. 13 p., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Beach Warren. Watteau. B.F.A. 12 p., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bean Betty Randolph. Art Today? B.F.A. 12 p., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Beeman Everett [C.]. Shaker Design. B.F.A. 13 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Beerman Herbert. Linear Devices in Drawing. B.F.A. 45 p., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Beggs Thomas Montague. The Works of Pietro Perugino and Abbott H. Thayer have a Similar Tendency toward the Expression of a Spiritual Ideal. B.F.A. 33 p., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Benke W[alter] R. Humanism in the Italian Renaissance. B.F.A. 9 p., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bennett Sally (Mrs. John W. Freeman). Sprayed Metal as a Sculptural Technique: Work of Robert Amendola. B.F.A. 11 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Benson John William. Functional and Expressive Anatomy. B.F.A. 14 p., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bernheimer Franz K. Considerations on Mannerism. M.F.A. 28 p., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bernstein Judith. A Self-Inquiry into a Painter's Studio Processes. M.F.A. 7 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bernstein Lawrence [Albert]. The Function of Art in the Light of Analytical Psychology. B.F.A. 12 p., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Besnia Howard John. A Comparison of Portrait Sculpture in the Tempyo and Kamakura Periods. M.F.A. 25 p., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bishop Barbara [J.]. Persian Miniature Painting. The Timurad School and Bihzād. B.F.A.[1943]. 13 p., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bittleman Arnold. A Study in the Psycophysical [sic] and Psychological Aspects of Color Mixture. B.F.A. 30 p., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Blahitka Mary M. Art in Education. B.F.A. 18 p., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Blake Marjorie. A History of Fashion Magazines in the United States. B.F.A. 32 p., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bloomer Kent C. Statement of Purpose. M.F.A. 22 p. Portfolio., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Blumenthal Herbert [D.]. Serigraphy. B.F.A. 22 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Blytheman Douglas G. A Thesis. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Boghosian Varujan. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 14 p., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bopp Emery. The 20th Century and Religious Painting. B.F.A. 31 p., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Borgatta Robert E. Modigliani. M.F.A. 28 p., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Boyden Frank. Thesis M.F.A. 13 P. Slides., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Brakke Perry M. Two Years. M.F.A. 11 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Brand Marion. The Sienese School of Painting. B.F.A. 10 p., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Brandfonbrener Conrad. A Stylistic Analysis of the Painting of Amadeo Modigliani. B.F.A. 32 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Brandfonbrener Conrad. The Spatial Illusion in Seventeenth and Nineteenth Century European Landscape Painting: An Analysis of Means and a Comparison of Objectives. M.F.A. 63 p., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bransby, Eric J. An Analysis and Discussion of the University of Illinois Mechanical Engineering Building Mural. M F.A.[1952]. 19 p., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Brodeur Clarence A. The Training of the Artist. M.F.A. 43 p., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Brodney Edward. "Isms" in Painting since 1900. B.F.A. 13 p., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Brody Sheldon A. "Style", the Machine, and Man. B.F.A. 20 p., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Brody Sheldon A. The Development from Static to Dynamic Photo-Documentation. M.F.A. 116 p., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Brookes C[harles] M. Jr. Restoration of the Church of St. Simeon Stylites, Early Christian Monument at Kalat-Seman, Northern Spain, Dating 450 to 550 A.D. M.F.A. 6 p., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Brooks Eleanor [R.]. Piero Della Francesca. B.F.A. 10 p., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Brooks Mabel R. Development of Greco-Buddhist Art in India and China. B.F.A. [1930]. 24 p., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Brown Leona S[chur] (Mrs. Robert W. C.). The Theological and Icono-graphical Development of the Doctrine of the Holy Trinity from Pre-Christian Times to the Renaissance. B.F.A. 192 p., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Brown Leona S[chur] (Mrs. Robert W.C.). Botticelli and Michelangelo: Philosophy and Form. M.F.A. 94 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Brown Richard M. Observations on those who are Passing through and those who have Passed through Art Training. B.F.A. [1943]. 14 p., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Bryden Robert [S.]. Object, Idea and Art. B.F.A. 30 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Burgin Victor. Personal Statement. M.F.A. 11 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Burk Thomas. Some Essentials of Subject and Expression in Art. B.F.A. 15 p., 1921 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Burnham Wilbur H. Jr. The Rebirth of Secular Stained Glass. B.F.A. 10 p., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Burns Robert [C.]. [Untitled (on color)]. B.F.A. 89 p., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Burstein Sephine[J.]. Contextualism and Cubism. B.F.A. 22 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Byrne Jackie [Jacqueline M.]. Lithographs of Toulouse-Lautrec: His Life and Influences. B.F.A. 18 p., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Cain Michael. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 16 p., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Calabrese Dan[iel] L. The Creative Process: An Inquiry into It"s[sic] History, Psychology and Esthetics. M.F.A. 32 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Caldwell William V. The Technique of Gilbert Stuart. B.F.A. 35 P., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Camp Larry Ray. On My Painting. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Camp Russell R. Auguste Rodin: An Appreciation. B.F.A. 7 p., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Carlberg Norman. A Sculptural Screen Unit. B.F.A. 4 p., undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Carlson E. Thor. "Madonna col Bambino e San Giovannino" di Sandro Botticelli. B.F.A. 33 p., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Carroll Richard and Coluxar: Research in Lumia G. Scott Wright Jr. B.F.A. 37 p., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Carter Susan J. A Statement. M.F.A. 11 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Case Isabel Marie. The Portraits of Charles Despiau. B.F.A. 18 p., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Cassino Michael [P.]. The Vision of Trecento Painting. B.F.A. 21 p., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Cassino Michael [P.]. Mondrian and Geometric Form. [M.F.A.] 37 p., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Chapin Stephen. On My Work. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Chaplin George E. The Japanese Folding Screen. B.F.A. 32 p., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Charles Peter Evan. On My Sculpture. M.F.A. 15 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Chazen Harold. An Esthetic Approach to Photography. B.F.A. 20 p., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Christ-Janer Victor [F.]. Decoration, Representation, and Expressionism as Related to Style in America. B.F.A. 9 p., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Cicotello Louis M. Thesis. M.F.A. 6 p., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Clancy Patrick Michael. Valences. M.F.A. 17 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Cofrancesco Paul Ferdinando. The Life of Michelangelo. B.F.A. 11 p., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Cogswell Dorothy McIntosh. History of Landscape Painting. B.F.A. 13 p., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Cogswell Dorothy McIntosh. The French Romanesque Figured Capital. M.F.A. 111 p., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Cohen John. Functional Aspects of Line in painting. B.F.A. 68 p., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Cohen John. An Investigation of Contemporary Weaving of the Peruvian Indians. M.F.A. 82 p., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Cole George Henry. Modern American Mural Painting. B.F.A. 11 p., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Conlon William Bernard. A Personal Analysis of Works Executed at Yale University. M.F.A. 12 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Connor Russell. [Untitled portfolio]. [M.F.A.] 10 p., [1959?] (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Corwin Arthur. A Limited Study of the Visual Properties of a Surface Structure of the Sphere. B.F.A. 18 p., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Cota Blaine A. Jr. Fifty Years of Ballet Dancing in the United States. M.F.A. 133 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Cotter Michael. Mondor Cotter's East Rock Thesis. M.F.A. 13 p., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Crapster Thaddeus Greaves Jr. Glass in Construction. M.F.A. 36 p., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Crescenti Louis J. The Decorations of Tiepolo. B.F.A. 13 p., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Crivy Joseph. Triptychs. B.F.A. 23 p., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Crowe Walter Q. Guernica: 20th Century Enigma. B.F.A. 25 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Crutcher Albert B. The Nature of Parallel Rays of Light with Respect to Form for Purposes of Drawing. B.F.A. 10 p., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Cummings Bradford C. Transmitted Light: Its Theory and Function. B.F.A. 20 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Curry C[harles] F. Jr. Spring 1942. B.F.A. 12 p. (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Dalrymple Ogden Rafferty. Some Conclusions regarding Sculpture and its Design. B.F.A. 10 p., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Darrow Alexandra I. Russian Icons. B.F.A.[1933]. 14 p., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Davenport Diane. The Re-orientation of Mural Design to Contemporary Architecture. B.F.A. 20 p., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Davenport Joy. An Analysis of Figure Ground in Persian Miniatures. B.F.A. 108 p., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - DaVia Louis. Domenico Veneziano. B.F.A. 9 p., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Davidson Daniel John. In Search of Full Emptiness. M.F.A. 10 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Day John Hamblin. On the Virtue of Selfless Art. B.F.A. 33 p., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Day John Hamblin. Byzantine Art: Its Sources, its Development, its Continuation in Russia. M.F.A. 116 p., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - de Bretteville Peter. The New Brutalism. 21 p., undated (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - De Carlo Charles. American Water Color Painting. 34 p., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - DeLauro Giuseppe Nicola. Liberation and Bondage in Art. B.F.A. 12 p., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Deley Joseph. A Description and Discussion of the "Matisse Chapel" at Vence. B.F.A. 80 p., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - De Lucia Raymond [H.]. Dominico Ghirlandaio. [B.F.A.] 9 p., [1938?] (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - DeNatale A. Richard. A Comparison of Hand Lettering and Type and their Use as Two Dimensional Design Media. B.F.A. 14 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Denenberg Allan Neal. Festivals and Pageantry during the Renaissance in Italy. B.F.A. 78 p., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Denenberg Allan Neal. A Study of a Mediaeval Visual Complex with Supporting Examination of a Renaissance Visual Complex. An Analysis of a Historical Continuity of Visual Forms towards the Realization of a Method with which to Plan a Visual Complex to Serve Contemporary Man. M.F.A. 117 p., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Denner William A. Thesis Project. M.F.A. 7 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Derderian Ara Arakel. The Artist and our Society. B.F.A. 15 p., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Derderian Ara Arakel. Some Factors concerning the Artist in our Society. B.F.A. 10 p., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - De Vito Ferdinand. A Mosaic Innovation in Architecture. M.F.A. 28 p., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Dietemann Charles A. The Social and Educational Aspects of Art[B.F.A.] 12 p., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - DiMeglio Antonio. 7-31-40. M.F.A. 7 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Dizon Vicente Alvarez. Art of the Filipinos. [B.F.A.] 23 p., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Doggett Jane. A Series of Photographs from the Southern Appalachian Mountains. M.F.A. 26 p., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Domonkos A[lexander] H. Color in Painting. B.F.A. 7 p., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Drysdale [T.] Dornacilla. The Solving of Wall-Space by the Paintings of Giotto, Puvis de Chavanne and Orozco. B.F.A. 15 p., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Dube Eleanor. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 19 p., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Dufour Paul A. The Roman Catholic Influence on the Primitive Art of the African Negro. B.F.A. 28 p., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Duncan Malcolm Graeme. Art and Steel. B.F.A. 11 p., 1929 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Dunlap David. [Untitled portfolio], M.F.A. 25 p., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - DuPen Everett George. The Essentials of Sculptural Form. [B.F.A.] 14 p., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Durfee [Carder] Hazard. Art and Ideals. B.F.A. 24 p., 1939 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Eberhard, W[illia]m Burke. El Greco: As a Painter in his own Times and as a Master Today. B.F.A. 21 p., 1940 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Eberhart, Richard P. Another Spiritual Conversion. M.F.A. 8 p Slides., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Ecklund, Jacqueline. The Growth and Development of the Modern Movement in Architectural Interiors. B.F.A. 26 p., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Edwards Emlyn R. The Objectivity of Art. M.F.A. 47 p., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Elmgren George Richard. Development of a National Style in Persian Miniatures. B.F.A. 41 p., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Elmgren George Richard. Study of Mola Applique Art of Richard the San Blas Indians (Tule). M.F.A. 51 p. Slides., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Elston Helen Aczkiewicz. How Raphael Composed. B.F.A. 32 p., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Engel Edward F. The American School of Painting. [B.F.A.] 4 p., 1925 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Epstein Beverly A. Considerations in Framing. B.F.A. 19 p., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Etchison Bruce. A Brief Survey of Etching through the Sixteenth Century. [B.F.A.] 20 p., [1948?] (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Etchison Bruce. An Analysis of the "Baptism of Christ" from the School of Lorenzo di Credi. M.F.A. 48 p., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Evans Elinor [L.]. Implications of Some Gestalt Principles of Perception in a Group of Contemporary Paintings. M.F.A. 90 p., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Evans P[ryce] H. Thesis on Painting. [B.F.A.] 12 p., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Evans Rosemary Haughton. Color in Sculpture. B.F.A. 19 p., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Eveleth Florence May. Characteristics of Early Gothic Tapestries. B.F.A. 10 p., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Fabry, Alois Victor Jr. Tempera, a Medium for Wall Decoration: Its Use and Application. B.F.A. 15 p., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Fabry, Jaro. Honoré Daumier. B.F.A. 8 p., [1933?] (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Falbo, Joann. Statement of Purpose. M.F.A. 30 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Farnam, Suzanne Silvercruys (Mrs. Henry W. Jr.). Sculpture in Belgium during the Past Fifty Years. B.F.A. 11 p., 1928 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Farnham Frances E. Albrecht Durer: A Discussion of his Style. B.F.A. 7 p., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Fecher, Meyer. A Comparative Study of the Still Lifes of Chardin and Cezanne. [B.F.A.] 27 p., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Feldman Walter S. The Negro: An Individual in American Painting. M.F.A. 45 p., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Feltus Alan Evan. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 17 p, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Ferriter, Clare. The Japanese Color Print. 10 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Feuerlicht, Herbert Alan. An Investigation into the Nature of the Architectural and Sculptural Forms of the Ancient Aztec Culture of Mexico in an Attempt to Ascertain Some of the Reasons for their Taking the Forms they did. B.F.A. 40 p., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Fink Herbert L. Creative Printing. [M.F.A.] 101 p., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Fisher Leonard Everett. Figures of Fantasy. M.F.A. 52 p., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Flack Audrey [L.]. The Visual Change from Space to Depth. Depth as Used by Abstract Expressionism. B.F.A. 13 p., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Fleming Guy. The Educational Filmstrip: A Study of its Functions and Disciplines as a Primary School Teaching Tool. [M.F.A.] 50 p., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Floeter Kent. Thesis Project. M.F A. 33 P. Portfolio., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Fogelman J[ames] K. Oil Painting in the Yale School of the Fine Arts. [B.F.A.] 15 p., [1948?] (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Forrest Rita Virginia
    General note
    See: box 11, folder 544
  - Franklin Richard W. Thesis. 10 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Franzheim Elizabeth [S.]. An Historical Survey of Two Modes of Expression in Art. B.F.A. 25 p., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Freedman Mary C[atherine] N[eidigh] (Mrs. Daniel x.). An Early Chinese Painting: Attributed to Ku K" ai-chih. B.F.A. 51 p., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Freeman Mrs. John W.
    See: box 1, folder 34
  - Freiheit Audrey Jane. Textural Change and Development in Mayan Ceramics. B.F.A. 20 p., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Fried Norma Shirley. Prehistoric Art. B.F.A. 14 p., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Friedberg Richard [S.]. Some Notes on my Sculpture. [M.F.A.]8 P Slides., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Friedman Robert S. Sculpture in the Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries. B.F.A. 13 p., 1952 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Froelich Janet. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 6 p., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 180)